ARIEL GIANATIEMPO

linkedin.com/in/gianatiempo | gianatiempo@gmail.com | +54 11 2766-2212 | gianatiempo.netlify.app

SENIOR FRONT END DEVELOPER

Senior developer with over 17 years of experience specializing in optimizing systems and enhancing efficiency. Experienced in debugging, enhancing performance, and overseeing successful migrations. Strong communication skills and a collaborative mindset, with a focus on achieving measurable results.

TECH SKILLS

JavaScript, React, React Router Dom, Material UI, ESLint, Prettier, TypeScript, REST, Axios, fetch, CRA, React Query, React Testing Library, Redux, Context API, MSW, Redux-Thunk, Ant Design, Cypress, GraphQL, Vite, Vitest, Webpack.

SOFT SKILLS

Results-driven, Problem-Solving, Attention to Detail, Analytical Thinking, Team Player, Technical Mentorship.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

V3 Cybersecurity - Senior Front-End Developer

Apr 2023 - Present - Remote

- Joined the company as a solo front-end developer tasked with modernizing their MVP.
- Migrated their MVP to utilize the Ant Design library and other cutting-edge dependencies, resulting in a 60% performance boost and reduced deployment and development times.
- Expanded the application by incorporating new features and enhancements while following a monthly release schedule.

Tech Stack: React, Vite, TypeScript, Context API, React Query, fetch, REST, React Router Dom, Ant Design, React Testing Library, Vitest, ESLint, Prettier, MSW.

System One - Senior Front-End Developer

Jul 2022 - Feb 2024 - Remote

- Migrated the Material UI library from an early beta version to an up-to-date release, eliminating recurring bugs caused by the incorrect implementation of basic/core components.
- Migrated two core application areas, simplifying their logical processes, dependencies, and implementations. This led to a 90% reduction in bugs in the two weeks following the release and a complete elimination of bugs in those areas.
- Created a separate project utilizing Playwright, Cucumber, and TypeScript to empower the QA team, enabling the creation of automated tests to enhance quality and prevent regression issues.

Tech Stack: React, Webpack, JavaScript, Context API, React Query, fetch, REST, Redux, Redux-Thunk, React Router Dom, Material UI, React Testing Library, ESLint, Prettier.

Austin Software - Senior Front-End Developer

Dec 2021 - Jun 2022 - Remote

- Maintained and developed a platform in the pharmacy industry.
- Proposed several improvements, tools, and best practices.
- Defined and updated the coding rules for the entire monorepo using ESLint and Prettier. Updated the codebase to comply with the new rules. Enabled TypeScript for the frontend application, defined, updated, and created new types to complete the upgrade.
- Trained team members to easily adopt ESLint/Prettier with VSCode and simplify their workflow.

Tech Stack: React, CRA, TypeScript, Axios, GraphQL, React Router Dom, Material UI, ESLint, Prettier.

- Joined a brand new team where I participated in the development of a new greenfield application. Proposed and improved the application architecture, linting rules, and coding standards. Introduced new tools and refactored all tests to leverage their capabilities.
- As an extracurricular activity, I joined a team that reviews coding exercises to assess candidates and provide feedback to HR as part of the hiring process.
- As an extracurricular activity, I led an Ignite group on React, best practices, and related topics.
- As an extracurricular activity, I acted as a technical lead and mentor for an internship program that
 involved six developers. The objective was to develop an application to automate tasks for
 non-technical teams. This includes tasks ranging from analysis and design to development, testing,
 and ultimately, production release.

Tech Stack: React, TypeScript, React Query, fetch, React Router Dom, Material UI, React Testing Library, MSW, ESLint, Prettier.

J.P. Morgan & Chase - Associate / Technical Lead

Apr 2020 - Jan 2021 - Argentina, BA

 Led a team of three React developers, which was later expanded to six, in migrating from Flex to React. We migrated the code as we discovered the features and capabilities of the existing codebase. Whenever possible, we extended and updated the workflow to successfully remove all deprecated software components within eight months.

Tech Stack: React, CRA, JavaScript, React Query, Axios, React Router Dom, Material UI, ESLint, Prettier.

J.P. Morgan & Chase - Associate Software Developer

Nov 2019 - Mar 2020 - Argentina, BA

Joined a team of five front-end developers to design a system for tracking users' claims. Improved tooling that reduced local build time by 50%. Defined a set of enhancements and best practices, such as folder structure, linting, and prettier rules. Refactored the entire state management architecture. This improvement enhanced overall performance, eliminated duplicated code, and addressed most of the technical debt in the project. Mentored and assisted junior members and new joiners in adapting to the team and company culture.

Tech Stack: React, CRA, JavaScript, Axios, Redux, Redux-Thunk, React Router Dom, Material UI, React Testing Library, ESLint, Prettier.

Globant - Web UI Developer

Sep 2018 – Oct 2019 - Argentina, BA

 Developed an internal product for the company by incorporating new features, enhancing code quality, and adhering to team best practices.

Tech Stack: React, CRA, JavaScript, Axios, Redux, Material UI.

Tecnosoftware - Front-End Developer

Mar 2018 - Aug 2018 - Argentina, BA

• Delivered new features. Mocked UX design and proposed adjustments to align with the design system. Refactored code to facilitate future migrations to a new technology stack.

Tech Stack: AngularJS, JavaScript.

Buffa Sistemas - Front-End Developer

May 2016 - Feb 2018 - Argentina, BA

 Maintained a set of custom jQuery plugins. Collaborated with UX/UI teams to design interfaces and landing pages for a wide range of purposes. Trained new team members in the use of our custom plugins.

Tech Stack: JQuery, AngularJS, JavaScript, HTML5, Sass, Jira, Git, Grunt.

- Engaged in development efforts by creating and implementing new API endpoints. Contributed to the expansion and enhancement of the overall system's functionality.
- Developed front-end components and services, and demonstrated proficiency in full-stack development. This included integration between the front-end and back-end components to ensure a cohesive user experience.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to understand project requirements and translate them into solutions. This involved code reviews and collaborative problem-solving.

Tech Stack: AngularJS, JavaScript, Grails, MySQL.

Multiple Corporations - Web Developer

May 2007 - Feb 2015 - Argentina, BA

- Collaborated on the development of API endpoints, maintained, and enhanced existing features. This encompassed a diverse range of projects, showcasing adaptability and technical expertise.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams and clients using Scrum methodologies, and demonstrated effective teamwork and project management skills.

Tech Stack: Java 6, Hibernate, MySQL, Wicket.

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native English: Proficient Italian: Advanced

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

<u>EF SET Certificate (C2 - Proficient)</u> EF SET | Apr 2024

React 16 - The Complete Guide (incl. React Router 4 & Redux)

Certificate of Completion, Accelerated ES6 JavaScript Training

Certificate of Completion, Introduction to TypeScript

Udemy

Certificate of Completion, Agile Software Development Kleer | Dec 2016 Universidad Tecnológica Nacional - Systems Engineering (Incomplete) 1997 - 2001